Greetings , my friend . We are all interested in the future ,
for that is where you and I are going to spend the
And remember my friend , future events such as these will affect
You are interested in the
unknown , the mysterious , the unexplainable .
That is why you are here . And now , for the first time ,
we are bringing to you the full story of what happened on that fateful day .
We are giving you all the evidence , based only on the secret testimonies
of the miserable souls who survived
this terrifying ordeal . The incidents , the places ,
my friend we cannot keep this a secret any longer .
Let us punish the guilty ,
let us reward the innocent . My friend ,
can your heart stand the shocking facts about grave robbers
from outer space ?
Plan 9 From Outer Space
All of us on this earth , know that there is a time to live ,
and that there is a time to die , yet death is always a shock
to those left behind .
It is even more of a shock , when death ,
the proud brother , comes suddenly without warning .
Just at sundown , a small group ,
gathered in silent prayer around the newly-opened grave
of the beloved wife of an elderly man . Sundown of the day ,
yet also the sundown of the old man 's heart ,
for the shadows of grief clouded his very reason .
The funeral over , the saddened group left the graveside .
It was when the gravediggers started their task
that strange things began to take place .
Fifteen to four .
Yup , right on schedule . There 's the ol ' San Fernando Valley
out there now . - You better radio in
for landing instructions , Danny . - Right , Jeff .
Burbank Tower , this is American Flight 812 , over .
Wouldn 't surprise
me any if he 's asleep this time of the morning .
American Flight 812 , this is Burbank Tower . If I were asleep
you 'd never get on the ground .
Your case maybe you 'd be up there for good . Over .
You got me that time , Mac . This American Flight 812 requesting -
Burbank Tower to American Flight 812 , over .
Holy mackeral . - Burbank Tower to American Flight 812 ,
are you in trouble ?
Trouble ? - Take a look for yourself .
What in the world ... - That 's nothing from this world .
Burbank Tower to American Flight 812 , are you in trouble ? Are you in trouble ?
Mayday , mayday . Stand by , Burbank Tower .
Do you suppose the passengers saw it ?
I doubt it . Most of them are asleep . But it was quite a jolt , Jeff . I 'll check .
Good . We 'll get them ready for landing . Keep it quiet until we get instructions .
Right .
American Flight 812 reporting to Burbank Tower , over .
D 'you hear anything ? - I thought I did .
Don 't like hearin ' noises .
' Specially when there ain 't s 'posed to be any .
Yeah , sorta spooky-like .
Maybe we 're getting ' old . - Whatever it is it 's gone now .
That 's the best thing for us too . Gone .
Yeah , let 's go .
The grief of his wife 's death
became greater and greater agony .
The home they had so long shared together ,
became a tomb .
A sweet memory of her joyous living .
The sky to which she had once looked , was now only a covering for her dead body .
The ever-beautiful flowers she had planted with her own hand ,
became nothing more than the lost roses of her cheeks .
Confused by his great loss , the old man
left that home , never to return again .
At the funeral of the old man , unknown to his mourners ,
his dead wife was watching .
First his wife , then he . - Tragic .
Tell me something . Why was his wife buried in the ground ,
and
he sealed in a crypt ? - Something to do with family tradition .
A superstition of some sort .
Well , it 's getting ' dark . We 'd best be on our way .
Then , as two of his mourners left his final resting place .
Minutes later , the police , lead by Inspector Daniel Clay ,
arrived at the scene .
Who found him ? - The man and girl .
Medical , uh , examiner been ' round yet ? - Just left .
The morgue wagon oughta be along most any time .
You get their
statement ?
Yeah , much as we could . They 're pretty scared .
Finding a mess like this oughta make anyone frightened .
Have one of the boys take the guy and the girl back to town . You take charge .
Okay Inspector . What 're you gonna do ?
Look around a little . - Pretty dark out there .
Once you get beyond those lights you won 't be
able to see your hand in front of your face .
I will get one of the flashlights from the patrol car .
You be careful Clay . - I 'm a big boy now , Johnny .
Looks like a bobcat tore through them .
Yeah .
Say Lieutenant ,
d 'you get that funny odour ? - How could I miss it ?
Oh , that 'll be the morgue wagon now .
That 's the fifth siren in the last hour . - Oh , something 's happened down at
the cemetery . A lot of police cars and lights .
I stopped but I didn 't see anything .
Oh well , whatever it is , the morning paper will carry the whole story .
You seem to still be up there somewhere .
Maybe I am .
I don 't think I 've ever seen you in this mood before .
I guess it 's because I 've never been in this mood before .
Something about your flight ?
Yeah .
What happened , Jeff ?
I saw a flying saucer . - A saucer ?
You mean the kind from up there ? - Yeah , or its counterpart .
I was shaped like a huge cigar . Dan [ something ] saw it too .
When it passed over , the whole compartment
lighted up with a blinding glare .
Then there was a tremendous wind that practically
knocked us off our course .
Well did you report it ?
Yeah , radioed in immediately and they said well
keep it quiet until you land .
Then as soon as we landed , big army brass grabbed us
and made us swear to secrecy about the whole thing .
Oh , it burns me up . These things have been seen for years .
They 're here , it 's a fact .
And the public oughta know about it .
There must be something more you can do about it .
Oh no there isn 't . Oh , but what 's the point of making a fuss .
Last night I saw a flying object that
couldn 't possibly have been from this planet .
But I can 't say a word . I 'm muzzled by army brass .
I can 't even admit I saw the thing .
Sounds like Clay 's in trouble .
Bet that apparition we saw had something to do with it .
Come on .
Is he dead ? - Yeah .
He 's messed up as bad as those two back there .
S 'pose that saucer or whatever it was had something to do with this ?
Your guess is as good as mine , Larry .
But one thing 's sure . Inspector Clay is dead
murdered ... and somebody 's responsible .
You 're in charge now , Lieutenant .
Yeah , guess I am . Kelton . - Yes Sir ?
Get back up to the car and get on the radio .
Tell the coroner he 's gotta make another trip out here .
Well how ' bout the lab boys ?
Well who do you think we left back at the car ,
boy scouts ? Come on , Larry .
Greater love hath no man , than to lay down his life for another .
It is always difficult to have last words
over the grave of a friend . And Inspector Daniel Clay was a friend .
A dear friend to me and to all of us .
The bell has rung upon his great career .
Now we lay him to rest . A rest well deserved , but so premature .
People turning south from the freeway were startled when they saw
flying saucers high over Hollywood Boulevard .
A woman , startled by the sight in the sky , telephones the police .
There comes a time in each man 's life ,
when he can 't even believe his own eyes .
Saucers seen over Hollywood .
Flying saucers seen over Washington D.C.
The army convoy moved into the field .
Rockets were quickly set up .
Colonel Tom Edwards , in charge of saucer field activities ,
was to make the greatest decision of his career .
He made that decision . Colonel Edwards gave the signal to fire .
Then as swiftly as they had come , they were gone .
Even to the piercing eye of radar and the speeding jet fighters .
Quite a sight , wasn 't it Sir . - A sight I 'd rather not be seeing .
Are you worried about them Sir ?
Well , they must have a reason for their visits .
Visits ? Well that would indicate visitors .
Are big guns the usual way of welcoming visitors ?
We haven 't always fired at them .
For a time we tried to contact them by radio , but no response .
Then they attacked a town . A small town , I 'll admit .
But nevertheless a town of people .
People who died . - I never heard about that Sir .
Well , it was covered up by the higher echelon . Take any fire ,
any earthquake , any major disaster ,
then wonder . Flying saucers , Captain ,
are still a rumour .
Officially .
Looks like we beat them off again Sir .
What do they want ... where are they from ... where are they going ...
They , Sir ? Who ?
Oh , this is a training manoeuver , Sir .
We only did a little practice firing at the clouds .
Yeah . I wonder what their next move will be .
What will their next move be ?
Your space commander has returned from Earth .
Send him in .
You have your report ?
We had to pull in here to Space Station 7 for regeneration .
We 're returning to the planet Earth immediately thereafter .
What progress has been made ? - We contacted government officials .
They refuse over existence .
What plan will you follow now ?
Plan 9 . It 's been absolutely impossible to work through these Earth creatures .
Their soul is too controlled .
Plan 9 ... ah yes . Plan 9 deals
with the resurrection of the dead .
Long-distance electrodes shot into the pinion
pituitary glands of recent dead .
Have you attempted any of this plan as yet ? - Yes Excellency .
How successful has it been ?
We have risen two so far . We shall be just as successful on more .
The living ... they have no suspicion of your movements ?
We had to dispose of one policeman .
However , none of those risen have been seen .
At least , not by anyone who still remains alive .
It 's too bad it must be handled this way . However it must .
Those who take from the grave will lead the way for our other operations .
Yes , Excellency . - Continue on . Report to me
in two Earth days .
I feared His Excellency wouldn 't take our report this well .
Well had he been dealing with our own people
his reaction would have been completely different .
He understands the difficulties of the Earth race .
What do you think will be the next obstacle the Earth people will put in our way ?
Well , as long as they can think we 'll have our problems .
But those whom we 're using cannot think . They are the dead .
Brought to a simulated life by our electrode guns .
You know , it 's an interesting think when you
consider ... the Earth people , who can think ,
are so frightened by those who cannot : the dead .
Well our ship should be regenerated . We better get started .
I still think you oughta go in town and stay with your mother until I get back .
This is our home and nothing 's going to take me from it .
Besides , most men try and keep their wives from going home to Momma .
That 's not the point . - That 's all the point there 's going to be .
Now toddle off and fly your flying machine , Darling .
But if you see any more
flying saucers , will you tell them to pick another house to buzz ?
Don 't worry about me .
Oh you 're the only thing I do worry about . Oh forget about the flying saucers .
They 're up there . But there 's something in that cemetery ,
and that 's too close for comfort .
The saucers are up there . And the cemetery 's out there .
But I 'll be locked up in there . Now off to your wild blue yonders .
You promise you 'll lock the doors immediately ?
I promise . Besides , I 'll be in bed before half an hour is gone ,
with your pillow beside me . - My pillow ?
Well , I have to have something to keep me company while you 're away .
Sometimes in the night when it does get a little lonely ,
I reach over and touch it , then it doesn 't seem so lonely anymore .
A crazy kid .
I do love you , Darlin ' .
See you Thursday . - Goodbye , Honey .
You know I 'm not leaving here until you 're locked safely inside .
All right , Darling .
If you 're especially nice I may even lock the side door .
And be sure you keep the yard lights on .
You 're mighty silent this trip , Jeff .
You haven 't spoken ten words since takeoff .
I guess I 'm preoccupied , Danny .
We 've got thirty-three passengers back there that have time to be preoccupied .
Flying this flybird doesn 't give you that opportunity .
I guess you 're right , Danny .
Paula ? - Yeah .
There 's nothing wrong between you two ? - Oh no , nothing like that .
Just that I 'm worried , she being there alone and
those strange things flying over the house and
those incidents in the graveyard the past few days . It 's just got me worried .
Well , I haven 't figured out those crazy skybirds
yet but I give you fifty to one odds
the police have figured out that cemetery thing by now .
I hope so .
If you 're really that worried Jeff why don 't you radio in and find out ?
Mac should be on duty at the field by now .
He could call Paula and relay the message to you .
Hi Edith .
Hi Silents . I haven 't heard a word from this end of the plane since we left the field .
Jeff 's been giving me and himself a study in silence .
You boys are feudin ' ? - Oh no Edie , nothing like that .
Hey Edie , how about you and me balling [ bawling ? ] it up in Albuquerque ?
Albuquerque ? Have you read that flight schedule Boy ?
What about it ?
We land in Albuquerque at 4 am . That 's strictly a nine o 'clock town .
Well I know a friend that 'll help us - - ...
Let 's have a problem first , huh Danny . - Ah he 's worried about Paula .
I read about that cemetery business .
I tried to get you kids to not buy too near one of those things .
He thought it 'd be quiet and peaceful there .
No doubt about that . It 's quiet alright , like a tomb .
I 'm sorry Jeff , that was a bad joke .
Say . , I almost forgot what I came in here for .
How 's the coffee situation ?
Mmmm that 's for me . - That sure wouldn 't hurt anything , Edie .
Okay , I 'll be right back . And say Jeff , make that call to your wife .
Huh , not only will she throw water on my Albuquerque plan but now she 's
repeating herself .
How ' bout that Albuquerque ball ? - I can 't resist your charm , Danny Boy .
Residents near the cemetery paid little attention to the blast of thunder
and the flash of lightning .
But from the blast , arose the moving figure of the dead old man .
Hello ? Who ?
Mac ? Well , hi Mac .
Sure I 'm all right .
I just fell asleep .
Tell Jeff I 'm all right .
Okay Mac . Thanks for calling . Goodnight .
Mrs. Trent . Mrs. Trent . What 's wrong ?
They 'll be at the hatch in a moment . You can open it now , Tanna .
Turn off the electrodes quickly . They can 't tell us from anyone else .
It 's tough to find something when you don 't know what you 're looking for .
I don 't think the Lieutenant does either .
Then what 're doing out here ? I was off duty an hour ago .
Ah don 't ask me any questions . I 'm just a hardhand [ hat ? head ? ] just like you .
What do you suppose that noise was ?
Whatever it was it 's no more strange than the
other things happening around this cemetery .
Spirits like Old Farmer Caulder talked about .
Heh . Maybe .
The only spirits he saw tonight were those I smelled on his breath .
Well don 't forget Mrs. Trent claims to have seen them too .
She didn 't have anything on her breath .
She was hysterical .
Well true , she was frightened , and in a state of shock .
But , don 't forget that torn nightgown and the scratched feet .
Yeah I hadn 't thought of that .
I guess that 's why you 're a detective lieutenant
and I 'm still a uniformed cop .
Sometimes it 's only the breaks , Larry . In the meantime let 's get - ...
Lieutenant , Lieutenant . Did you hear that ? - How could we help it ?
It sure was strange . - Know what it was ?
No more than you do .
If it weren 't for orders I 'd get out of here right now .
It was a saucer .
A flying saucer ? What makes you say that ?
You remember the noise we heard the other night ?
We were knocked to the ground , how could I forget ?
Exactly , but you 're not remembering that sound .
There you 're wrong , Lieutenant .
I 'm with a fact the sound is similar , but what about the blinding light ?
Well haven 't you heard ? Many times a saucer hasn 't had a glow ,
or a light of any kind for that matter . - That proves it . What next Lietenant ?
Maybe this doesn 't mean much ,
but uh Jamie and me found a grave that looks like it 's been busting into .
What ? Where ? - Why uh why ...
Come on man out with it , we haven 't got all day to waste .
Uh , just over there beyond the crypt . - All right , show us the way .
Look , here it is Lieutenant .
Ah it 's been broken into all right .
Strange . If someone had broken in , the dirt should be piled up here somewhere .
It looks like it 's fallen in into the grave .
Larry you 'll be out of that uniform before you know it .
Do we have the right to look down there Lieutenant ?
Ah , technically no .
Well , this spot looks familiar , though .
We shouldn 't investigate any further without the permission of next of kin .
Let 's go get it .
How ?
I see what you mean , the gravestone 's down there .
Well , let 's go down and find out who 's grave it is .
How ? - By going down and finding out .
Are you sure you mean that Lieutenant ? - If I didn 't mean it I wouldn 't have said it .
Scared ?
Well , why do I always get hooked up with these spook details ?
Monsters , graves , bodies ,
oooh all right .
Casket 's here , but nobody 's in it .
Can you read the name on the casket ?
It 's too dark . Give me a flashlight .
How ' bout a match ? - We sure could try it . Let me have them .
It 's Inspector Clay 's grave . But he ain 't in it .
But meanwhile , in the Pentagon , in Washington DC ...
Try G2 ...
Yes of course , I 'll keep in touch .
Come in , Colonel Edwards . Close the door . At ease , Colonel .
Thank you , Sir . - Sit down .
I understand , Colonel , you 've been on tap for many of our saucer attacks .
I 'm in charge of field operations , Sir .
You believe there are such things as flying saucers , Colonel ?
Yessir . - You 've seen them ?
Yessir .
You realize there 's a government directive
stating that there is no such thing as a flying saucer ?
Yessir .
Do you stand by your statement that you 've seen flying saucers ?
Well , uh
yessir .
This could mean a court marshall . Admitting this against direct orders .
General Roberts , may I speak freely ?
You may .
How could I hope to hold down my command
if I didn 't believe in what I saw and shot at ?
I , uh , like you Colonel . - Thank you , Sir .
There are flying saucers .
There 's no doubt they are in our skies . They 've been there for some time .
What 're we going to do about them ?
Who knows ? - Then , uh , they really are there ?
I thought you were convinced of that . - I am .
We 've had contact with them .
Contact ? How ? - Radio .
They speak our language ? - Well not quite .
We received messages from their space ships .
For a while it came in as just a lot of jumbled noise .
And now , Sir ?
Well since they first uh tried contact with us by radio ,
we 've developed a language computer .
A machine that breaks down any language to our own .
General , uh , what 's this all got to do with me ?
Well you 've been in charge of saucer field activity for a long while .
I think it 's about time you heard these recordings . Do you mind ?
Mind ? Huh , I 'm anxious .
This is Eros , a space soldier from a planet of your galaxy .
I fully realize our language differences , however I also know you finally have
perfected the dictorobitary , or as you on Earth put it ,
the language computer . So you can now understand that which I speak .
Since the beginning of your time , we have been far beyond your planet .
It has taken you centuries to even grasp what we developed eons of your years ago .
Do you still believe it impossible we exist ?
You didn 't actually think you were the only inhabited planet in the universe ?
How can any race be so stupid ?
Permit me to set your mind at ease .
We do not want to conquer your planet . Only save it .
We could have destroyed it long ago , if that had been our aim .
Our principal purpose is friendly .
I admit , we have had to take certain means which you might
refer to as criminal ,
but that is because of your big guns
which have destroyed some of our representatives .
If you persist in denying us our landings ,
then we must only accept that you do not want us on friendly terms .
We then have no alternative but to destroy you before you destroy us .
With your ancient , juvenile minds , you have developed explosives
too fast for your minds to conceive what you were doing .
You are on the verge of destroying the entire universe .
We are part of that universe .
This is our last -
That 's the end of that one .
Atmospheric conditions in outer space often interfere with transmitting .
How many of these recordings do you have General ?
An even dozen up to now . This was the last one .
We received it over a month ago .
Do you think they mean business ? - We can 't afford to take any chances .
Come over here . You ever been to Hollywood ?
Oh a couple of times . A few years ago . - You 're going to be there in the morning .
Just a few minutes from Hollywood , in the
town of San Fernando , reports have come in
of saucers flying so low the exhaust knocked people to the ground .
There have even been stated claims of saucer landings .
Major Carlson will replace you while you 're out there .
You 're the best man for the job of attempting to contact them .
Find them , Colonel . See what in hell it is they want .
All right , Sir .
These are confidential reports , Colonel . Read them over carefully on the plane ,
turn them over to intelligence when you get to Los Angeles .
They 'll have further orders for disposition .
Yessir .
Colonel Edwards ? - Yessir ?
Good luck . - Thank you , Sir .
We are ready to report , Excellency .
You are many days late . - It was unavoidable .
We tried to transmit via televisor , but atmospheric
conditions made transmission impossible .
You should have transmitted as soon as conditions permitted .
I thought time was of the essence .
Suspicion has fallen upon our movements .
Our ships have been viewed near the point of operations .
And what has this extra time gained , Eros ?
We have successfully risen three of the dead ones .
Permit me to see one . - Bring in the big one .
Use your small electrode gun .
I have taken two ships from your command .
But ... that will leave only my ship .
It is necessary that you continue your mission alone .
I have need of your other ships elsewhere .
Even though you have risen three of the Earth dead ,
the plan is far from successful ,
and you Eros , must prove it an operational success before
more time ,
energy , and ships , may be spent on it .
We will not fail . Everything is on our side .
Not everything . You do not have the live Earth people .
You report that your ship was viewed at scene of your present operations ?
That is correct .
They have been viewed many times , but not at the scene of operations .
Something must be done about that .
Stop him Tanna . He 's close enough . Turn off your electrode gun .
No . No . Stop him Tanna .
I can 't get it , it 's jammed . - Stop him you fool .
Drop the gun to the floor , Tanna . The metal will break contact .
[ Gasping ] That was too close .
Yes .
Bring the giant here that I may get a better look at him .
Yes , he 's a fine specimen . Are they all this powerful on planet Earth ?
This one is an exception , Excellency .
What are the other two like ? - One is a woman , the other an old man .
An old man , you say ? - Yes , Excellency .
This gives me a plan . Put the big one away .
Pick up your electrode gun .
Make sure it 's in working order before pointing it at him .
Whatever made it jam must have been cleared by the fall .
Take him back to the ship .
The old one must be sacrificed . Re-land on Earth .
Send the old one to enter a dwelling .
Then cut off the electrokinetic and turn on your ship 's decomposure ray .
The result will astound those watching . Astound them enough to delay their
attention until you have gained your other recruits from the cemetery .
Yes , Excellency . It 'll be done .
Report to me when this has been accomplished .
Eros , the Earth people are getting to that which we fear .
Since they will not listen or respect our existence ,
they cannot help but believe our powers when
they see their own dead walking ' round again ,
brought about by our advancement in such things .
As soon as you have enough of the dead recruits ,
march them on the capitals of the Earth , let nothing stand in your way . Their own
dead will be used to make them accept our existence , and believe in that fact .
Mr. and Mrs. Trent ... this is Colonel Edwards from Washington DC .
Good evening , Colonel . - Hello Colonel .
Colonel would like to ask you a few questions .
Questions ? What about , Colonel ? - May I , uh , sit down ?
Oh , I 'm sorry , please do .
I want to ask you about your strange experience
the other night , when you saw the flying saucer .
After that the police brought me home .
I hope I never see such a sight again .
Well after your description I don 't think I 'd want to see it either .
One thing
more ... after you were forced to the ground by that blast of wind ,
was it a hot or cold blast ? - It 's kind of hard to explain .
It wasn 't hot , wasn 't cold , it was just a terrific
force . We-we couldn 't get off the ground .
The light blinded me so badly I couldn 't see a thing .
We could only feel the pressure of the wind , until it was gone .
When the glare left us ,
we could see a glowing ball disappearing off in the distance .
Which way ? - Toward the cemetery .
This is the most fantastic story I 've ever heard .
And every word of it 's true , too .
That 's the fantastic part of it .
We found a lot of suspicious things out in that cemetery .
Then again , didn 't find anything to base a fact or suspicion on .
Hey , do you hear anything .
You see anything out there Kelton ?
Too dark , Lieutenant .
But something 's started stinking awful bad .
There 's something out there .
What do you make of that ?
You got me . It didn 't look that way a minute ago .
What about your man ?
Oh , in the excitement I forgot all about Kelton .
Oh , he 'll be all right in a few minutes .
Did you see that thing ? Did you get it ? - We got it .
What was it ? It didn 't fall ... I fired every bullet I had .
So did I. I don 't know what it was or what happened , but unless that bag of bones
can reassemble itself , it 's out of the running now .
Colonel I 've been out here so often you 'd think I 'd taken a lease on this place .
Not a long lease , I hope .
I see what you mean . But you know , I can 't help but feel the answer 's out here
somewhere .
Is the uh girl safe ?
Mrs. Trent you 'd better stay with the car . - Stay here alone ? Not on your life .
Modern women ...
Yeah , they been that way all down through the ages .
Especially in a spot like this .
Kelton . - Yessir ? - Stay with Mrs. Trent .
All right , Lieutenant .
Now you stay close to the officer , Honey . - I 'd feel safer with you .
Now the Lieutenant knows best .
Oh I don 't like it , but I guess there isn 't much I can do about it .
You have a gun ? - No .
Know how to use one ?
After four years in the Marine Corps ?
Here . - You think we 'll need these ?
You can never tell . Let 's get going .
What do you expect to find out here ?
Well there 's only one answer to that Mr. Trent ,
we 'll know when we find it . Inspector Clay 's grave is right over here .
Is that the one you told me was broken into ?
Yes .
This it ? - Yeah .
Looks to me like someone had broken out instead of in .
I figured that , but that 's impossible . - I wonder .
Look , Colonel , some things just can 't happen .
Yeah well after that apparition that was draped across Mr. Trent 's
patio , I would say we should keep our minds open to anything .
Look , Colonel , I 'm a policeman . I 've got to deal in facts .
But , I guess I 'll have to go along with you . You know I bet my
badge right now we haven 't seen the last of those weirdies .
They 'll discover our ship soon . - You going to let them find us ?
It 's the only way . These are the same men who have been so close so often .
They must be halted before they can inform others about us .
But there were others in the car . - They 'll be taken too .
Send the big one to get the girl and the policeman . I 'll
turn on the dictorobitary so we may converse with them .
You know , maybe we 're barking up the wrong tree .
One thing a policeman learns , Mr. Trent , is patience .
Where the burn spot you mentioned . - Right over the - look .
We 'll investigate , but move carefully .
A moment or two more , and you will be the first live Earth people
ever to enter a celestial ship .
Wow ... boy , how could anything that big hide for so long a time ?
Never heard metal sound like that before .
What do you see ?
Only my reflection . Must be some kind of one-way glass .
How do you get into this thing ? - I 'm not sure I want to find out .
They 're just outside .
You can open the outer hatch now .
You goin ' in that thing ? - That 's what we 're here for .
I don 't know , the way these things speed around
we might just get in there and pft . Off it goes .
That 's a chance we take .
Well , I took a chance on those earlier airplanes . Might just as well
see what the inside of one of these looks like . Got your guns ready ?
I tell you one thing , if a little green man jumps out
at me I 'm shooting first and asking questions later .
They 're in the outer chamber now .
Eros , do we have to kill them ?
Yes . - It seems such a waste .
Well wouldn 't it be better to kill a few now than , with their meddling , permit
them to destroy the entire universe ?
You 're always right , Eros . - Of course .
But those are not my words , those are the words of the Ruler .
Now you two stay right where you 're at .
We will do as you command . For the moment .
No for the moment about it . You just do as I tell you .
You do not need guns . - Maybe we think we do .
They would be of no use to you now .
They 've been mighty useful before on flesh and blood ,
and you two look like you 've got a lot of both .
True , they would be effective upon us . If you
were to have the opportunity to use them ...
Mister , if you don 't get away from that control board I 'll show you just how
effective they can be .
Shall we talk now , or wait ? Your friends will be here shortly .
What friends ? - Those you left at the vehicle .
If you 've done anything to Paula ... - Take it easy Mr. Trent .
Oh I assure you , no harm has come to her . Would you like to see ?
Next time you try that I won 't aim at the board .
You 're a headstrong young man .
I was only going to turn on the televisor so you could see her movements .
Go ahead , my friend , but move very carefully .
She 's only fainted .
You fiend . - I ? A fiend ? ...
I am a soldier of our planet .
I ? A fiend ? We did not come here as enemies .
We came only with friendly intentions . To talk .
To ask your aid .
Our aid ? - Yes .
Your aid for the whole universe . But your governments
of Earth refused even to accept our existence .
Even though you 've seen us , heard our messages , you still refused to accept us .
Why is it so important that you want to contact the governments of our Earth ?
Because of death . Because all you of Earth are idiots .
Now you just hold on , Buster . - No you hold on .
First was your firecracker , a harmless explosive . Then your handgrenade .
They began to kill your own people a few at a time . Then the bomb , then a larger bomb .
Many people are killed at one time . Then your scientists
stumbled upon the atom bomb . Split the atom .
Then the hydrogen bomb , where you actually explode the air itself .
Now you [ audio jump ] brings the destruction
of the entire universe , served by our sun .
The only explosion left is the solaronite .
Why there 's no such thing . - Perhaps to you .
But we 've known it for centuries . Your scientists
will stumble upon it as they have all the others .
But the juvenile minds you possess will not comprehend its strength , until it 's too late .
You 're way above our heads .
The solaronite is a way to explode the actual particles of sunlight .
Why that 's impossible .
Even now , your scientists are working on a way to harness the sun 's rays .
The rays of sunlight are minute particles .
Is it so far from your imagination they cannot do as I have suggested ?
Why a particle of sunlight can 't even be seen or measured .
Can you see or measure an atom ? Yet you can explode one .
A ray of sunlight is made up many atoms .
So what if we do developed this solaronite
bomb ? We 'd be even a stronger nation than now .
Stronger . You see ? You see ? Your stupid minds ... stupid . Stupid .
That 's all I 'm taking from you . - Get back here you jerk .
Let him finish .
It 's because of men like you that all must be destroyed .
Headstrong , violent . No use of the mind God gave you .
You talk of God ?
You also think it impossible that we , too , might think of God ?
You , who wear the uniform of your country . You see , I wear the uniform of my country .
Yes , we 've had to use drastic means to get to you , but you left us no alternative .
When you have the solaronite , you have nothing . Nor , does the universe .
You speak of solaronite , but just what is it ?
Take a can of your gasoline . Say this can of gasoline is the sun .
Now you spread a thin a line of it to a ball , representing the Earth .
Now , the gasoline represents the sunlight , the sun particles .
Here we saturate the ball with the gasoline , the sunlight .
Then we put a flame to the ball . The flame will speedily travel around the Earth ,
back along the line of gasoline to can ,
or the sun itself . It will explode this source , and spread
to every place that gasoline , or sunlight , touches .
Explode the sunlight here , Gentlemen , and you explode the universe .
Explode the sunlight here , and a chain reaction will occur , direct to the sun itself .
And to all the planets that sunlight touches .
To every planet in the universe . This why you must be stopped .
This is why any means must be used to stop you .
In a friendly manner , or as it seems , you want it .
He 's mad .
Mad ? Is it mad that you destroy other people to save yourselves ?
You have done this .
Is it mad that one country must destroy another to save themselves ?
You have also done this . How then is it mad that one planet
must destroy another that threatens the very existence -
That 's enough .
In my land , women are for advancing the race , not for fighting
man 's battles . Life is not so expansive on my planet .
We don 't cling to it like you do . Our entire aim is for the development of our planet .
What happened to you ? - How come you 're all alone ?
I asked for lots of help .
You sounded drunk or something on the radio .
If I didn 't see it with my own eyes I would never have believed it .
Believed what ?
It was horrible . And he almost broke my shoulder .
Look , what are you trying to say ? If you don 't make sense
we 'll never get to the bottom of this . Now who slugged you ?
Inspector Clay .
What ?
It was Clay all right , only not like we remembered him .
Well his grave was busted into , wasn 't it ?
Next you 'll tell me you saw skeletons .
We did , earlier . - Now I know you 're off your rocker .
All of us saw , the Lieutenant , the Colonel , everybody .
Where 's the Lieutenant now ? - We 've gotta find them .
Mrs. Trent is gone . I was left here to guard her .
Then Clay showed up and put me out of the running .
And the second time tonight and I 'm getting darned tired of it .
Which way were they going ? - Oh , that way .
Come on .
Then one day it could all be gone , in one big puff of smoke
and ball of fire . All that out there ,
the stars , the planets ,
all just an empty void .
You two had better come along with us .
Come with you ? Where ? - The police station .
So it seems you think you have the upper hand .
Look out there .
Jeff .
She is unharmed , but he would kill in seconds if I so choose .
Holy cow .
Look there .
It 's Clay all right , there 's no mistaking that . - And he 's got Mrs. Trent .
Get your gun ready .
From all I 've seen tonight guns won 't do any good .
Clay is dead , and we buried him . How are we
going to kill somebody that 's already dead ?
Dead . And yet there he stands . That other one earlier I emptied a full clip into him .
I 'm seeing it , that 's the only reason I 'm listening to you .
Look , I 've got an idea . Hurt him or not , we 've got to try something .
I 'm going to sneak up behind him and whop
him over the head . That oughta make him move .
Follow me . Even when Clay was alive he couldn 't run fast enough to catch me ,
so when he does , you grab Mrs. Trent and run
like lightning in the opposite direction .
Oh , you think it will work ? - Know anything else to try ?
Oh , I 'll be all right . Take care of the others .
Your men have felled the big one .
This could only happen because the electrode ray is off .
He 'll walk again when I turn it on .
Hold it , right there .
Suppose the Lieutenant and the others are in that thing .
Well suppose there are martians or something in there .
Come on , let 's go .
Open up in there , open up .
Get that door open .
Colonel I wouldn 't know one switch from another .
Hold on Eros , I 'll have the ship in the air in a minute .
Get out of here , Jeff . The ship 's on fire .
Eros .
Eros everything 's on fire . Hurry , wake up Eros . Eros , Eros , wake up , wake up .
Eros . Eros wake up , Eros . God wake up .
Oh , I wonder if that 's the last we 'll see of them ?
Perhaps , but sooner or later there 'll be other .
Look .
Have they caught that woman , that thing yet ?
Hey that 's right , there 's another ghoul running loose .
And it 's my guess that she 'll look like him .
With the ship and the ray gun gone , they have no control .
We got to hand it to them though , they 're far ahead from us .
Fire . Eros . Aaaaaaaaah .
My friend , you have seen this incident based on sworn testimony .
Can you prove that it didn 't happen ?
Perhaps on your way home , you will pass someone in the dark ,
and you will never know it , for they will be from outer space .
Many scientists believe that another world is watching us this moment .
We once laughed at the horseless carriage ,
the aeroplane , the telephone , the electric light , vitamins ,
radio , and even television .
And now some of us laugh at outer space .
God help us ... in the future .
Base Subtitles by FredFal